♪ In the
not-too-distant future ♪
♪ Way down in Deep 13 ♪
♪ Dr. Forrester and TV's Frank ♪
♪ Were hatchin' an Evil Scheme ♪
♪ They hired a temp
by the name of Mike ♪
♪ Just a regular joe
they didn't like ♪
♪ Their experiment
needed a good test case ♪
♪ So they conked
him on the noggin ♪
♪ And they shot him into space ♪
- [Mike] Get me down!
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot Roll Call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- Show yourself.
♪ Gypsy ♪
- I'm not ready!
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- Hello there!
♪ Croooow ♪
- That's one O!
♪ If you're wonderin' how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La-La-la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000! ♪
(clanking and creaking)
(beeping)
(whirring)
(thudding)
(whooshing)
- I can't make it through
the trilogies myself.
- Hi everyone, Mike Nelson here.
Crow T Robot and I
have finally agreed
to play Dungeons and
Dragons with Tom Servo.
Frankly, I can't work
up a lot of enthusiasm--
- Quiet, fool!
The Dungeon Master has arrived.
Welcome both of you to my
fantasy role-playing group.
Have you selected
your characters?
- Uh, no, I didn't know...
- I, character, I didn't...
- Silence!
Pick a character from this,
the Middle-Earth Chrestomathy
- Oh, okay, um I'll be
Delmar the Elfin King.
- Ah!
- Yeah, me too,
Delmar the Elfin King.
- No no, I command that you are
Gorlob, Dwarf Prince of Valdar!
- Alrighty, then I'm
Gorlob, Dwarf Prince of--
- You are both walking on
a Tremidafalian footbridge
when you run across a fourth
level Balrog, what do you do?
- I really don't know.
- Quickly, grab your wand,
you fool, grab the wand!
- Uh, I'm grabbing my wand,
I don't know, is it helping?
- No no no, use fireballs,
you idiots, fireballs!
No!
Too late, you are both devoured.
- Oh, well live and learn.
- Oh, you know what?
The Balrog casts the Spell
of Zortan on you, my friend.
- Not Zortan, no, not Zortan,
no, no, no, no! (sobbing)
- We'll be right back.
- I must take my own life.
- Ah, that's gonna
happen, I guess.
- I guess.
(Tom chanting)
- That gets us out of a game.
- Nice move!
(upbeat music)
(Tom sobbing)
- I'm sorry, Servo,
but enough is enough.
- Oh, but I was about the enter
a deep level of Blinephaha!
- Servo, you've entered at
a deep level (babbling).
- Hey!
- Hey Rivendell and
Mordor are calling.
- Those are places!
- Oh, sorry.
- Clay, have you seen
my X-Men number 354?
- Frank, you're breaking
my concentration!
I wanna get all my back issues
of Starlog organized in time
to tape tonight's
episode of TekWars.
- TekWars is on, that's right!
(doorbell ringing)
- I wonder who that could be.
- I don't know.
That's right, I forgot
all about TekWars.
I must see tonight's
episode, it's supposed to...
(creaking)
- Hi!
I'm Bridget and this
is my friend Mary Jo.
We just moved in upstairs
to Deep 12, we're neighbors!
(Frank screaming)
- Clay, there are girls
here, actual girls!
- Uh, uh, uh, don't panic!
Um, there should be
some instructions
on what to do, uh, somewhere.
- Well, we've introduced
ourselves, who are you?
- I have lots of comic
books! (chuckling)
I keep them in plastic bags.
- Oh, yeah! (chuckling)
- We haven't seen the laundry
room, do you know where it is?
- Are we on a date?
'Cause it's okay
if we're on a date.
Frank and I have been on lots
of dates, haven't we Frank?
- Lots of dates, yeah.
Babylon 5 was on last night.
- Oh, yeah yeah yeah, it was!
(all awkwardly chuckling)
- Mike, you've got to help us!
We're on a date down here.
Could you uh provide us with
some kind of entertainment?
- Hi!
- It just so
happens I've written
a topical satirical
review that we call...
- [All]
Supercalafragalisticexpiala-wacky!
(Crow laughing)
- Let's go, let's go!
- I'm all set!
- Hand me that--
- I got it, I got it!
- Get out of the way!
(wacky music)
♪ I'm the government ♪
♪ I'm filled with
bloats and perks ♪
♪ I'm the government ♪
♪ I'm the reason nothing works ♪
- Boy, I tell you, it's not
easy bein' the working man,
but at least I've earned an
honest day's wage and I can--
- Thank you!
- Hey!
(wacky music)
♪ I'm the crime
bill, bang bang ♪
♪ I get shot at every day ♪
♪ I'm the crime
bill, bang bang ♪
♪ I'm opposed by the NRA ♪
♪ Bang bang ♪
(Crow choking)
- Hello, Mr. Senator.
My daddy's out of work
and he says that it's
because of the deficit.
So I saved some money
in my piggy bank
and I'm going to give it to
you to lower the deficit!
If an 8-year-old
kid can save money,
how come the government can't?
(wacky music)
♪ Honk honk ♪
♪ Beep beep ♪
♪ Government gridlock ♪
♪ Honk honk ♪
♪ Beep beep ♪
♪ Government gridlock ♪
♪ There's a traffic jam at
the Congress intersection ♪
♪ But the light is red
unless there's an election ♪
♪ Government sure
can get tacky ♪
♪ It's
Supercalafragalisticexpiala-wacky!!!
♪
(Dr. F and Frank
clapping and laughing)
- That's a funny one,
that was a stitch!
(both laughing)
- There's nothing
safe from you guys!
(both laughing)
- Oh, well Mike,
your movie this week
is called the Sword
and the Dragon.
We won't be watching it
because we're on a date.
- (yawning) Yeah, we're on a...
- Pass me the Punisher.
- Better double bag this.
♪ That's the Foreign
Policy Blues ♪
(alarm blaring)
- Oh, we got movie sign!
- [Crow] What about improv?
(clicking)
(whooshing)
(thudding)
(whirring)
(beeping)
(clanking and creaking)
(adventurous music)
- [Tom] Joseph Harris?
- Here!
- Sig Shore.
- Present!
- [Mike] Boy, could
you imagine pullin'
one of them things
into the boat?
- [Tom] Ah, the international
symbol for no dragons.
- [Mike] When once
or tries to get along
with an incorrigible dragon!
(Tom gulping)
- [Narrator] Many many years
ago, there was a faraway land
on the other side of the world.
- [Tom] The Catskills!
- [Narrator] A land
richly endowed by nature.
(Tom gulping)
- Wow!
- [Narrator] A land
of golden lakes,
rolling hills, and fertile soil.
But hovering over this once
happy land like an evil cloud--
- [Mike] (gasping)
George Clinton!
- [Narrator] Was the
face of a ruthless enemy.
- [Tom] I said no cameras!
- [Narrator] Kalin, Chief of
a plundering tribe of Tugars--
- At your Lincoln
Mercury dealer!
- [Narrator] Who
ravaged the land!
- [Mike] South-central Copasan.
- [Narrator] Pillaged
and burned its cities!
- [Tom] King Friday's kingdom!
- [Narrator] Leaving desolation
and despair in
their terrible path!
- And bad editing in their wake!
- [Narrator] Across the breadth
of a countryside once peaceful,
the hordes of Kalin
savage Tugars' road,
Killing,
burning,
ravishing.
- [Tom] Itching, flaking.
- [Narrator] Their brutality
unmatched in history!
- [Mike] Coming soon
to a theater near you.
- [Narrator] Our story begins in
a quiet village in
this besieged land.
- Made out of toothpicks!
- [Narrator] A village
which lives in constant fear
of Kalin and his invaders.
- [Tom] So move!
(somber music)
- [Mike] Man, she's a fox.
- Take a picture, why don't ya?
- [Tom] (sighing) The perv
is looking at me again.
- [Mike] Don't look,
you'll only encourage him!
- God had given him
the body of a warrior.
- Blades are useless and he
cannot move a single step.
(bell ringing)
- The Tugars are coming!
- [Tom] Hekawis!
- Hide, the Tugars!
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] Well, they
spent a lot of money
on a fortress but no gate!
(Tom and Crow chuckling)
- Man this movie is already
50 times more expensive
than all the movies
we've seen put together!
- [Tom] That chars!
(people clamoring)
- [Mike] Come on, honey!
There you go!
- Hey, no one invited
me to the pillaging!
- May you be cursed,
murdering scum!
- [Tom] Go girl!
- Right on woman!
(laughing)
- She will be quite a tasty
dish to take to our king!
- I'm not that tasty,
I'm mostly gristle!
- There's a caravan,
must be gold there!
- [Tom] Hey, watch the
hands, don't get fresh!
(screaming)
- Leave my child alone!
- [Mike] Let Pat
Carroll go, you beast!
(screaming)
- Help!
- Dan Haggerty!
- Hands I cannot
lift to help them.
- [Mike] I bowled last
night and I'm pretty stiff.
- Wagons East!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Hey, the
caterers are here!
♪ Where are we
goin' tonight sir ♪
♪ All I know is
that I'm on my way ♪
- [Crow] This is
not the shortcut!
(crashing)
- [Mike] Doctor Who!
(horses whinnying)
(hoofbeats thundering)
- At long last, our nation says
no to renaissance festivals!
- [Tom] Finn ropin' here
at the Mongol Rodeo!
- Spare me, I beg you!
- [Raider] Come closer,
my blubbering one,
and let me take a look at you!
You seem to be well-fed,
you're heavy enough!
- [Mika] Oh, please
spare me, sire!
I'll do anything
you wish, anything!
- [Mike] Wash my car and pick
up Tina from piano lessons!
- Swear you'll serve me!
- Yes sir, I will, I will!
You can have anything I own!
Here, see this?
- A finger towel, great!
- [Mike] And here's a soap
sliver, please spare my life!
- Listen well, son of misery!
- [Tom] You know my dad?
- Send this to us as a
signal to Chief Kalin
that the Prince's soldiers
have left the city.
I shall await your signal
at the river in seven moons.
Hear me, oh miserable one!
- Danny Kaye!
- If you fail us,
if you deceive us,
you shall die like a dog!
- Ah!
(Crow barking)
(tense music)
- [Narrator] This was a
time of giants and dragons,
- [Mike] And low inflation.
- [Narrator] When brave
and fearless men rose up
to perform mighty deeds
against the forces of evil.
- [Tom] I'm Mike Wallace.
- [Narrator] Mightiest
of all was Invincor,
mighty defender
of the righteous.
- And a nice guy!
- Who raised his magic sword
across the breadth of the land
to smite the
enemies of the just.
- [Mike] Riding Lori Barbero.
- [Narrator] After many years,
when Invincor had grown weary
with age, his tasks were done.
- [Tom] He was given a farewell
banquet and a small TV.
- As ye travel far and wide,
O ye wandering pilgrims--
- [Mike] Uh, boss?
- Seek out a young man.
- [Mike] Hey, boss?
- Stout of heart, strong of
arm, and brave of spirit.
- And taut of buttocks.
- And when you find such a man,
give him this, my magic sword,
to defend our land
and our people
from all manner of enemies.
- [Tom] And get the
five bucks he owes me.
- [Narrator] His last deed
done, Invincor turned to stone
to become part of a legend
that would live for all time.
- [Mike] How many prologues
does this movie need?
- Then they harvested
the charcoal briquettes.
- [Tom] Boy, farmers
really need the rain, huh?
- [Mike] The heat is
blowing up my skirt!
- [Tom] Ow.
Ow.
- At least I saved this stick!
- I'm thirsty!
- [Tom] Oh, what's your poison?
- Patience, my son.
- [Mike] I'm
thirsty, I'm thirsty!
Next I suppose you'll
want something to eat!
I've never had anything to
drink and I've done just fine!
(somber music)
- [Tom] Ah, good, they
reached the ranger station!
- Good morrow to thee, stranger!
We are weary travelers,
what is thy name?
- [Ilya] I am Ilya
Muromets, son of Theodore.
- [Mike] You pay at
the first window.
- Could you bring us some water?
- [Ilya] Glad would
I be to serve you
but I cannot move
from this chair.
Come into my house
and drink your fill.
- Thank you!
Come!
- I should warn you,
I'm just a torso!
- [Tom] They're at
Jellystone Park.
- [Mike] He's got
a poster of Sun Ra!
- Greetings to thee, Ilya.
- Yeah yeah, could you
bring me a magazine?
- I know you gentle pilgrims
have traveled far and wide.
- [Tom] Member of FDIC.
- Tell me of the evils
that have befallen
our beloved country in
these days of darkness.
- Our poor and troubled land
is plunged into woe
deep as the sea!
Those cursed Tugars
plunder, rob, and kill!
- If only I had
my strength back,
I could help defend my
country in her hour of need.
- But I've been classified 4-F.
- [Tom] I could
beat this guy up!
- Drink the dew of
the magic grass, sir,
and perhaps thy
strength will return.
- [Mike] Here's
some Haley's M.O.
- Thank you, my son.
Drink this, young man,
drink hearty and pray.
- [Tom] Please sir,
could I have more?
- [Mike] Ilya likes
carrots, doesn't he?
- Doest thou feel the strength
returning to thy
veins yet, Ilya?
- I'm less thirsty.
- Yes yes, I can!
- [Tom] I'm coppin' a buzz!
- But...
- [Tom] The walls are moving!
(Ilya groaning)
- Splat!
- I still cannot move!
- Patience, my Ilya.
Thy strength shall indeed
return, I promise thee.
- [Mike] Uh, hold on,
I'm havin' a montage.
(tense music)
- It's the line
for Wild Mountain!
- [Tom] Whoa, that was
one a high colonic,
yes sir, I feel like a new man!
- Let's get you back to
your room, Mr. Togolson.
- [Mike] I'll take these,
I'll just wear them
out of the store!
- [Tom] I feel good all under!
First thing, I take
off the burlap dress!
(triumphant music)
- [Mike] And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
the Swedish Moses of Soul!
- [Tom] Ah, hey, who
left all my tools
laying around in the front yard?
- [Mike] I'm feeling
positively demonstrative!
I could almost tell
my wife I love her!
- Oh, I need to sit down for
a while, believe it or not.
- Take now the magic sword of
Invincor and be thou like him.
- [Tom] 'Cause we don't
want to carry it anymore!
- [Mike] This is the
best tasting sword ever!
- Thank you, good friends.
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Ah, I sold the sword
and bought some Finnish vodka.
- [Mike] Yep, pretty much!
- (sighing) How my hands yearn
to feel the good, rich earth
and the honest toil of
the farmer once again.
- Well, go ahead and
grab a plow, then!
- Work the fields
with my father.
- [Tom] I thought
he was the father?
- [Mike] It's a
good crop of stumps!
(cracking)
- Uh, hold on, I'll
get the Bobcat!
- [Tom] Ow!
(Ilya grunting)
(cracking)
- [Tom] Uh, we want that.
- Root up the tree stumps!
- [Mike] And we'll have
a tree stump of fun!
(crashing)
(Ilya grunting)
- I'll see how many
times I can skip this!
(splashing)
- [Tom] Sure, go ahead
and use the fjord
for your garbage dump, Ilya!
- Hard as stone now has been
no earth of my father's.
- [Mike] Grandpa, no!
- Soft as the down of a
swan will thou become.
- The mighty falcon
lifts his wings
and is ready to fly again.
- Our son is like a man reborn!
- His strong hands shall
help work our fields.
- The banjo becomes
angry at midnight!
What the hell are
you talking about?
- Forgive me, dear mother.
- [Tom] I overreacted.
- But I cannot till the
land or reap its riches.
Kalin and his plunderers
aim their deadly arrows
at the heart of our country
at this very moment.
- [Mike] Oh well!
- I cannot remain here
while our country suffers.
- So you're coppin' our again?
- Give me your
blessing, dear parents.
- [Tom] You want
the car, don't ya?
- Now I must go forth.
- What you tell us lies
heavy on my heart, my son.
- I go because I must,
Mother, my country needs me!
- I give you my blessing,
Ilya my son, go in peace.
- [Mike] Why are you
older than me, son?
- Guard against evil, my son,
and help your fellow man.
- [Tom] But not Murray.
- I shall remember your
wishes always, Mother.
- Hey, hey hey hey, hey hey,
you're in the wrong myth!
- You will need a strong horse,
I would like to
give you mine, Ilya.
His name is Chestnut Gray.
- [Mike] Oh, that's
okay, I'll walk.
(Chestnut Gray whinnying)
- Do not concern yourself
over his small size.
Bathe him three times in due
and he will grow
until he becomes
the mightiest of all the
steeds you have ever known.
- [Tom] Jeez, I'm
running late as it is!
- Well, let's get
you far enough away
where they won't
hear the gunshot.
- [Tom] No!
- [Ilya] Grow,
Chestnut Gray, grow!
- Isn't he supposed to bathe
him in Mountain Dew or?
- [Ilya] He thou as fleet
of foot as the deer.
- [Tom] Buy bonds
where you work or bank.
- [Ilya] Swim rivers
faster than the salmon.
Streak across the ground
swifter than the wolf.
Higher than the Falcon
winging through the sky.
- [Mike] Longer than there've
been fishes in the ocean.
- [Ilya] When a stranger
calls, hear him not,
but when you hear my voice--
- Run!
- [Ilya] Come swiftly
like the wind.
- Anything else, Your Highness?
- [Ilya] And we shall
be friends unto death,
in deed and in battle.
- [Mike] Oh, I don't do battle!
- [Ilya] Good Chestnut Gray.
- [Tom] Look, I got an
offer from Calumet Farms.
- [Ilya] Serve me
well, noble steed.
- [Mike] He is a
lonely, lonely man.
- Connery!
Snipes!
- [Tom] Daily affirmations.
- [Mike] The Duluth Chamber
of Commerce bids you adieu.
- And wherever Ilya went
he carried his pool cue.
- [Tom] Aw jeez, he cast
it right into the weeds!
(majestic music)
(raven cawing)
- [Mike] Nevermore!
- [Cryptic Voice]
Follow the right road
and you will find riches!
- [Deep Voice]
Follow the left road
and you will find a wife!
- [Eerie Voice] Go straight
ahead and you will find dead!
- Chestnut Gray, quit
doin' your impressions!
- [Ilya] Riches would
give me little joy.
- [Tom] But I'll
take 'em anyway.
- Now is no time
to woo me a wife!
- [Tom] But I'll
take one anyway.
- [Ilya] So I shall follow
the road that leads to death!
- I might not get
to death tonight,
I may spend the night
at serious injury
and head over to primitive
disability in the morning.
♪ No I don't wanna fall ♪
Chen, round up every
Finn on the island!
- Thou shalt seek shelter
in the southwest
corner of thy basement!
(bird screeching)
- [Mike] Where are the RUOSes?
- Oh, this is downtown death.
(bird screeching)
- [Tom] Woo woo!
- This movie has a real
View-Master quality.
- [Mike] Oh, why did
Invincor like this job?
(Chestnut Gray whinnying)
(Ilya grunting)
- [Wind Demon] Go straight
ahead and you will find death!
- Ah!
- Ugh!
Maybe he has a good personality?
(dramatic music)
- Whoa, blech, Dorito breath!
- [Tom] Dizzy Gillespie-esque.
- [Mike] Well,
that's always nice,
just blow the leaves
into the neighbor's yard!
- Couldn't the
wind just cry Mary?
- Do not fear this wind demon!
- [Mike] You know,
sometimes I wake up
and I feel like this guy looks.
- [Ilya] He cannot harm
you, Chestnut Gray!
- [Tom] Yeah, sure, let's go
down the road to death, fine,
what the hell was I thinkin'?
- Chestnut Gray is like the
Chevy Suburban of horses.
(crashing)
(laughing)
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah.
- Lucky shot!
- [Tom] Uh, I can
explain everything, heh!
- Looks like a fat owl this one
and yet he cries
rivers of tears!
- I'm a wind demon, it's my job!
- I shall take you to my Prince
and he will decide
what to do with you.
- [Mike] Okay, let me
put on my good fur.
- Princes, nobles, and warriors,
here I sit with you in judgment
and here with you
do I hold court.
If there be any wrongdoers,
let them be brought
before us for judgment.
- Bring up Al D'Amato!
(crowd murmuring)
- [Tom] I like
having court outside!
- This villain must be
punished, good Prince,
he tore my mare's tail off!
You must find a
suitable punishment,
for what he has
done is a bad thing!
- It is bad.
- He has also stolen
the Royal timber!
- He must be a villain!
- Yes, sire!
- Kris Kristofferson!
- It is true that
I did these things,
but I had very
good reason, sire!
He loaned me his
horse but no harness,
so I tied the wagon
to the horse's tail.
(crowd laughing)
That is how it happened, sire.
- Ha ha, it's the Finnish
version of Night Court!
- He should be sent to
prison, he must be punished!
- This is our verdict.
- I'll allow the DNA.
- You, Vagaran, give
him your horse to ride
through the forest until her
tail shall grow back again.
This is our judgment.
- Justice, Region
Prince, justice!
- [Tom] Get up, you brown noser!
- And you, young man, remember
you must return the horse
to Vagaran in good condition.
- And enter drug rehab!
- Yes, sire.
I swear it!
- [Mike] It's a kingdom
of Robert Borks!
- Radiant Prince!
Durbar the mighty warrior
has returned to the palace.
- [Tom] He's the artist formerly
known as Radiant Prince.
- Summon all the nobles
for a great feast
and see that all these
people are fed well!
- I need a veggie meal!
- [Tom] Can I bring my cousin?
- [Mike] I'm lactose-intolerant!
- [Crow] Can I have
the money instead?
- [Tom] But I don't like food!
- Our good and noble
Prince invites you all
to the feast at the palace!
(clanking)
(beeping)
(whirring)
(thudding)
(whooshing)
(clicking)
(loud ticking)
- Once, on the shore on
the great Northern Sea,
two men stood alone on a pier.
(wind whistling)
(waves crashing)
- Sven?
- Ja, Ole?
(foghorn blaring)
- There came in to me a thought.
(seabirds calling)
- Ja?
(dog barking)
- I will count the
boards of this pier.
- Ja?
- And you...
- You will count the
slits between the boards.
- You the boards
and I the slits.
- Ja.
(seabirds calling)
- (gasping) Begin!
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Six (yelping).
(splashing)
- And so you see,
when you're out of slits,
you're out of pier.
(dog barking)
(crowd singing in
foreign language)
- [Crow] It may be the wine,
Lars, but you're a pretty man.
- [Tom] Sven, no,
don't, you mustn't!
- [Mike] Who's the new guy?
- [Tom] We'll be showing
the Vikes-Packers game
in just a few minutes everyone.
- Excuse me, good people.
- [Mike] Where's the men's room?
- Which among you
is Prince Vanda?
- Why do you ask for the Prince?
A bumpkin like
you belongs there,
at the foot of the
table with the peasants.
- You are too harsh with
the stranger, Alexi,
let him be heard, perhaps
he brings important news.
- Yeah, like we're
the best buffets are.
- I came here not to
feast, good nobles,
but to serve my
Prince and my country.
- And I say you're
not fit to sit
at the same table with a noble!
- [Mike] No no no no no no!
- You, a noble?
More likely you joust with
milkmaids behind the barn!
- [Tom] I'm not gay!
(crowd laughing)
- He's the Finnish Oscar Wilde!
- Make way for the Nobel Mika,
bearing rare and costly
gifts for our Prince!
- Good health and
greetings, Radiant Prince.
- [Mike] Look, I don't
book openers anymore.
- I have collected all
taxes and tributes.
I was sorely wounded in
battle but I routed them all!
All your enemies!
- [Tom] Anyways, here's
some of the stuff we got.
- For you, dear Prince, for
you alone I would do it again,
I would gladly lay down my life.
- For a hamburger today!
- Radient Prince, I
bested the mighty Tsartag,
for you I would
gladly give my life!
- [Mike] No, no lick!
- So would we all,
every one of us!
- A wind demon attacked me
and I cut him to ribbons
in the enchanted forest!
- He lies, my Prince!
- [Tom] I saw him wet them
on the field of honor!
- I know that he has not even
set eyes on the wind demon.
- Who are you, good stranger,
and where do you come from?
- I am Ilya Muromets,
I am from Goldova,
my father has a small
farm there near the river.
- Oops, dropped a cufflink.
- And have you yourself
seen the wind demon?
- [Ilya] I will show him to you!
- [Mike] Say hello to the
nice people, wind demon!
- Here he is, the
evil one, not very big
but he's as mean as he looks!
- [Man] I've never
seen such a monster!
Command him to whistle
as loud as he can!
- [Woman] Can he
really create the wind?
- [Ilya] That he can do but
do not let him frighten you!
- [Tom] Do you eat lunch?
- Wait Alicia, please
do not run away.
- [Mike] Wang Chung with me!
- Someone will see us here!
- I do not care as
long as we're together!
- My brothers say I'm too
young to be wooed, Alexi.
- Statutory woo!
- You belong to me, Alicia.
(gasping)
- Oh, Captain Spaulding!
- Now whistle, you
ugly wind demon,
but only with half
of your strength!
- Clint Howard!
(Tom huffing)
- Now whistle, evil one, mm!
- [Mike] You know how
to whistle, don't you?
(wind demon heaving)
(wind demon whistling)
- Oh yuck, he was
eating crackers!
(dramatic music)
♪ The summer wind
demon came blowin' in ♪
♪ Roll up the barrels ♪
- Cleanups a breeze
thanks to wind demon!
- Alicia!
- Wacky sight gags
of ancient Finlandia.
- [Tom] Mrs. Rittenhouse!
- Man, I'm killin' tonight!
- [Mike] The wind
hooked me to a cable!
♪ Everyone knows it's Windy ♪
- [Mike] The wind demon
has killed a lot of people
but it's all in good fun!
- Stop him Ilya, make him stop!
- Stop him before
he blows us away!
- Stop, we've seen
enough, make him stop!
- Hold your breath,
spawn of the devil,
you have performed
your last evil deed!
- Hey, you asked me!
- No more children with
your blasts of wind!
- This country bumpkin is
quite a fellow, I think!
- [Mike] Yes, jolly
good, old man.
- [Tom] Ergidda,
ergidda, ergidda!
- Oh yuck, he's in the spittoon!
- [Mike] That was pretty
good, can he scat?
- Take this, Ilya, as a
reward for your service.
As for this demon, his
reward will match his deeds.
- [Tom] Put him in
my private chambers.
(wind demon hissing)
- I gotta blow, ha ha ha!
- [Alexi] You are a man
after my own heart, Ilya.
- [Mike] Wanna start a band?
- [Tom] And so ZZ Top was born!
- Take no offense of Alexi,
he has a quick temper
but he is a brave and
courageous soldier.
Let us be friends.
- I'm Bob from Marketing.
(triumphant music)
- We shall be friends!
(buzzing)
- Friends to the end, Ilya!
Your steed beside my own!
- Now let us make a pledge.
We shall be as brothers,
the three of us.
The younger brother
must heed the elder
and together we
shall venture forth.
- Together in good
and in bad we three!
- All for one and one for all!
- Yow!
- This must be our way.
Our country we shall defend
with our lives if we must!
- Bravo, Ilya Muromets!
- [Crowd] Bravo, Ilya Muromets!
Bravo, Ilya Muromets!
- [Prince] Put on the
armor for the noble,
Ilya, you have earned it!
- I thank you, Prince!
- Bad tidings, O Prince,
Kalin's envoys have
arrived at the city gates!
♪ We got a great big envoy ♪
- [Tom] Pavarotti
tour is in town!
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] Close the buffet!
- He's gonna blow!
- [Prince] Greet them
with bread and salt!
- Those swine who
laid waste our land,
I would rather
greet them with arms
than with bread and salt, sire!
- Those are very
bold words, Ilya.
Would you teach me how to rule?
First we shall hear this envoy,
then we shall decide
what course to take.
- [Mike] All right, if
that's how you wanna do it.
- [Tom] Sounds like
the stripper's on next.
- Somebody get me a
bucket, I'm gonna throw up!
- I come as an envoy from
the mighty Chief Kalin.
It is his will that you shall
pay him taxes and tributes.
For 12 years you must
pay these tributes to us,
else we will invade your
land and empty your coffers!
- [Mike] Damn liberals!
- [Prince] Eat and
drink your fill.
We shall pay what you ask,
we shall do what you command.
- [Tom] Here's your
appetizer, sir.
(clattering)
- Kalin's envoy (snorting)
shall not be bribed
with bread and salt!
- To send such a dolt as
an envoy is an insult!
- Does he not look like
a great fat ox to you?
- Who dares speak
such to Kalin's envoy?
I would strike him down
as soon as look at him!
Guard your tongue
or I'll cut it off!
- You come here
with words of war,
therefore we answer in
kind and we are prepared.
- Resistance is useless!
I will make you bow to
our mighty Chief Kalin!
- Your words of your boasting
shall die in your
throat, envoy of Kalin!
- I have heard enough!
Your head shall be
the first I chop off!
(whooshing)
- [Tom] Oh, it's a
Matt Groening gargoyle!
- By your own sword,
dog, you shall die!
(whooshing)
For Kalin!
- Oh, right in the love handle!
- [Tom] Jake and the Fatman
is different than I remember!
- [Mike] (chuckling)
Jake and the Fatman.
(crowd screaming)
Uh, anyone know why
we're retreating?
- Run, acursed dogs, run
back to your master Kalin!
- Yeah, babies!
- And tell him the same fate
awaits anyone he sends us!
Tell him we will fight,
we will pay no tribute!
(crowd cheering)
- [Tom] Oh boy, we're
safe again, woo!
(triumphant music)
- Come wash your hands,
oh noble soldier.
- [Mike] They're filthy!
- He is indeed a mighty
warrior, as mighty as Durbar!
- And of courageous of Alexi is!
- His strength exceeds
that of Invincor!
- For your gallantry I will
force for you a coat of armor
finer than the Prince's
own coat of gold!
- [Mike] Yeah, sure you will.
- Take this lance, it was
fraught for a mighty warrior!
- [Crow] He never claimed it!
- I thank you all, good people.
- [Mike] I'm outta of here!
- I shall try to be
worthy of your trust.
- [Man] The Prince!
- [Tom] The Royal Pants!
- Make way for the Prince!
- [Mike] Fabulous, the Prince!
Ooh, it's warmer than I
thought I was out here.
- For your service
to our people.
- [Tom] It's dry clean only.
- All hail Ilya Muromets!
(crowd cheering)
(Tom, Mike, and Crow grunting)
- Oh, we need lighter heroes!
- Oh, once again I'm not
invited, Finland is so cliquey!
- I must act quickly!
I must get rid of this new hero,
else I will have to
answer for myself
to Kalin and his terrible
band of cutthroats!
- [Mike] Thanks for the aside.
(upbeat music)
- And here is your share.
All of this, all the
gold for you, here.
(laughing)
And now for my share--
- [Tom] Microsoft stock!
- I will take what is
left, the captive maid,
who stands there waiting
anxiously for me! (laughing)
- Let me have her, Tartak, and
you can have all my silver!
- No, don't play
with your booby.
- Give her to me, you
can have all the gold!
- Not so fast!
- Ooh!
- You shall not
have her, nor you!
I will take the captive
maid to Chief Kalin!
- [Mike] Ow!
- He is sure to give me
half a kingdom for
this prize beauty!
(grunting)
- [Tom] Exit stage left!
- You'll never be, you
plundering thieves!
- Gypsies and tramps!
- [Ilya] She will be set free
to go home to her parents!
- [Mike] Uh, I'm
tryin' to sleep.
- Fear not, little one, they
shall harm you no longer!
I shall release you!
Nothing on this Earth--
- [Tom] Just let me
say goodbye to Glock!
- Not even a Tugar would
keep you from me ever again.
(crowd murmuring)
- [Man] The Prince!
- Look busy!
- I see you are
quarreling again, my
rich and worthy nobles.
- [Mike] So just
give me the remote.
- If I gave you free rein
you would tear our country
apart with your fighting.
Matthew Bradoa.o
- [Crow] You're gonna
hit me, aren't you?
- I have work for you.
You must prepare a caravan
of furs and copper--
- [Mike] I'm dead.
- And voyage out to sea!
- [Mike] Sure I wasn't doing
anything for the next 10 years!
(birds chirping)
(peaceful music)
- [Tom] It's the
Song of the South!
(woman singing in
foreign language)
- Woo, Freebird, come on, woo!!
(Tom singing gibberish)
- Ah, dinner!
- [Tom] Johnny Mercer lyrics
really make this song.
- [Mike] She did all the same
stuff at her last concert.
- Okay, we all drop on three!
It's a living!
- [Mike] Hey, I've
got a baby to deliver!
- [Tom] I rather be roadkill
than listen to this!
- How 'bout a tip, lady?
- [Mike] Well, I gotta go
spread the plague, bye!
- [Tom] Ah, magic of Heidi,
ladies and gentlemen!
- This song contains
satanic messages!
- [Tom] Hey, Red Foxx!
- Oh, Bunny Rich!
- Still spinning and
weaving, Velia, my love?
- [Mike] What's
with the oven mitts?
- The lonely thoughts, it has
been lonely here without you.
- I, too, have spent many years
of loneliness, my dear wife,
but that is all behind me
now, I am lonely no more!
- [Tom] I got a cat!
- In our marriage I have
found true happiness,
dearest Velia, a priceless gift.
- [Mike] Now, where
the hell's my dinner?
- But what is this?
- [Mike] How much did this cost?
- This cloth,
it's woven of gold, it glitters!
- It is not a cloth, it
is a magic tablecloth!
- Uh-huh.
- It is beautiful indeed!
For whom did you make it?
- Deb's wedding shower.
- For the one whom
I love the best!
- The milkman?
- Now you must rest from your
labors, my busy little wife!
- [Tom] Let us the nasty do.
- All these wonders.
The Earth offers it
all for us to glory in.
- [Mike] A beautiful sunset
in Branson, Missouri!
- [Tom] Hey, it's
the Nina, the Pinta,
and the Mongo Santamaria!
- (whistling) You can
almost see her hairline!
- Grieve not, my
sweet one, grieve not.
We do not part for long.
- [Mike] I know, that's
what I'm grieving about.
- I shall drive Kalin
and his wicked Tugars
from the gates of our
city once and for all
and rid our land of those
traitors who would betray it!
- [Tom] Okay, see
you after work!
- In this most bitter
hour of our parting,
tell me dearest one--
- Can I have the checkbook?
- Tell me truly of
your greatest wish.
- [Mike] Pudding,
lots of pudding!
- Bear me a son,
Velia, a brave son
to grow up strong and
be a great warrior!
- Merlin Olsen is
no action hero.
- The falcons in the sky,
they were witness to
our love, little Velia.
- [Tom, Mike, And Crow] Ew!
- If you should bear a son,
call him Little Falcon.
- [Tom] How 'bout Rick?
- And whenever I see a falcon--
- [Mike] Um, something.
- I shall think of my son.
- It is my greatest
wish to give you
the son you desire, my beloved.
- If you bear a son--
- I want to know
who the father is.
- Give him this ring.
It was given to
me by our Prince.
- [Mike] Oh, he's gonna give
her his letter jacket, too.
- That's enough now, we're
being too demonstrative.
(gentle music)
♪ Headin' out to Eden yeah ♪
- [Narrator] Once again,
Velia was to be
separated from her love.
- [Mike] She came over last
night and we just just talked.
- [Narrator] Ilya, fearing
another attack by the Tugars,
insisted that his wife accompany
the Prince's caravan
of furs and copper.
On the open sea
- The Gene Simmons book!
- [Narrator] He reasoned,
Velia would be safe from harm.
- Her singing will
keep everyone at bay!
(Velia singing in
foreign language)
- [Mike] Nice autoharp.
- [Tom] Hey lady, you're
puttin' the bass down!
- [Mike] Wanna grab an
oar, Nana Mouskouri?
(crowd yelling)
- [Tom] Boy, he
can whip up a horde
faster than you can
say Jack Robinson!
- [Mike] No, the other way!
- [Tom] Hey, it's
the undersea king
♪ Dum dum de dum de ♪
- [Man] The Tugars are coming!
- [Tom] The British are coming?
- Don't leave me,
they're coming!
- Turn the boat!
(dramatic music)
- [Mike] The Navy
SEALs are here!
- Hi, I'm Julie,
your cruise director.
(man screaming)
- Hey you nicked me!
(Velia screaming)
- [Mike] Come to Uncle Mongol.
- By the gods, here
she is again, that
pretty one for Kalin!
- Ha ha, fine!
(jovial music)
- [Tom] Ah, the
Magnificent Torkelsons!
- [Mike] Greetings
from Rosemary Clooney!
♪ Here comes a king, here
comes a big number one ♪
- White Track simulated film
snow, ask for it by name.
♪ Do doo lee doo do lee do ♪
♪ We're cold, we're cold ♪
♪ We're freezing, we're
freezing, we're freezing ♪
(upbeat music)
♪ Applesauce,
balderdash, and baloney ♪
♪ Flimflam foodle-diddle fudge ♪
♪ Hogwash, fooey,
and horsefeathers ♪
♪ Pithle, pish-posh,
poppycock, Pete and Pete ♪
♪ Ya sure you betcha! ♪
♪ Lutefisk Lutheran,
leather and pumpkin ♪
♪ Flibberty-gibbet,
phooey, yokeum ♪
♪ Twattle,
wangdoodle, wingding ♪
♪ Kickety-Knack no ♪
You guys so weird!
- But, but I'm a bunny!
Hop!
Hop.
- Oh, give it up!
(alarm blaring)
- Hey, I'm molting!
- [Mike] We got movie sign!
- [Tom] This is the most
humilating thing I've ever done!
(clicking)
(whooshing)
(thudding)
(whirring)
(beeping)
(clanking and creaking)
- [Mike] Hop, hop, hop.
- Matthew Bradova?
- [Tom] You're not
wearing that, are you?
- What is wrong?
- [Mike] I'm cold and I'm
wet and I wannao go in!
- Punish me not, O Prince,
please let me speak first.
- Okay, now punish me!
- Speak then!
- We were attacked
by a band of Tugars!
- [Tom, Mike, And Crow] Whee!
- They plundered the
caravan, took everything.
I escaped after spending
months in bondage.
- That was the good part.
- [Tom] Damn, and the Snow Days
Festival was going so well!
- Ilya Muromets, ha!
- [Mike] That's Italian.
- Why was he not there to help?
- Did I not tell
you, Radiant Prince?
He is a fool, he is not the
sort of man to be trusted, sire,
he should've been
there to help Matthew!
- For this I will banish
him from the court,
for three full years.
- Throw down your hotdogs!
- If you banish Ilya,
you exile our strength!
- Fond as I am of Ilya--
- [Tom] I hate him!
- This must be done!
He goes to the dungeon
to pay for his deed.
- [Mike] Executive
producer Steven Bochco.
- Greetings to
you, good soldiers!
- Hi.
- I see you serve our city well!
- There is little joy in our
service today I fear, Ilya.
- [Tom] I gotta work.
- [Soldier] Blame us not, Ilya,
the Prince has given orders,
you're not to enter.
- You jest, do you not?
I have ridden here
in great haste
to help rid the palace
of its traitors!
- Do not let him in the palace!
- [Mike] Not with his shoes on!
- The Prince's orders.
- This is your work, O
captor of the wind demon,
so brave and fearless
in battle, huh?
Velia has told me the true story
of your treachery and
deceit, traitorous villain!
- Ilya, you're not
wanted here anymore,
you have been banished!
- So you all conspire against
me, do you, my nobles?
- [Crow] Let me just...
- You will soon see how
I deal with conspirators!
- [Mike] Dig this!
(shattering)
- [Tom] He does gutter work!
- I think he should be
hanged soon as possible!
drawn and quartered!
- Let the Prince
decide to do with him!
- If the Prince
wants no more of me,
then I want no more of his
gifts you may tell him!
(Crow whistling)
As I drag this coat in the
snow by its dangling sleeve--
- [Mike] It gets filthy!
- So I shall drag those traitors
who have plotted against me!
- [Tom] Here, and no starch!
- You nobles are ready
enough to join in a feast,
what about the Tugars, huh?
Who among you is
ready to stand up
and fight when the Tugars come?
- They are brave men they are,
when the Tugars are far away.
- I will drive every traitor
from the palace, I swear it!
- You act too hastily,
brother warrior.
- The Prince is quick of temper
but he cools quickly, too.
He has sent me to fetch you,
come to the palace with me.
- (growling) My
honor is at stake!
I'll not rest 'til I've
exposed these scoundrels!
(crowd shouting)
- He's consulting
Black Oak Arkansas.
- Have you forgotten the
pledge we took, Ilya Muromets?
The younger brother
shall heed the older?
That was our pledge, Ilya.
- Our Prince is wise and
knows whom to send here.
No one could persuade me
to go but you, Durbar.
- [Tom] Dove Bar?
- Come, let us go
to the palace now!
- [Tom] Mm! (lips smacking)
- [Mike] Anyway, on Melrose
Place, oh, no more, shh!
- Why did you draw your bow
in anger beneath my window?
- To avenge the wrong you did
in accusing me unjustly, sire!
- The arrow did
not leave his bow.
- He has evil thoughts
of you, O Prince.
I saw him trample your
coat on the ground thusly
and threatened to do
the same to you, sire!
- Yes, I heard him threatened
to that a moment ago.
- Yes, he did it!
- [Tom] You're outta order!
The whole damn
castle's outta order!
- But I did not
threaten you, My Prince.
- [Nobleman] He is not
to be trusted, sire.
- He will stir the entire
court in the mutiny, sire!
- There's the little matter
of an unauthorized facts!
- Listen, already
they are rebellious!
- It is not in the streets
that treachery is planned,
O My Prince--
- [Mike] It's at a Chile's!
- It is right here in the
palace that it is hidden!
- Your words are empty, Ilya.
They are untrue.
- What shall we do
with this traitor?
- Away with him to the dungeons.
Feed him bread and water.
- Uh, then a salad,
then an appetizer.
- Perhaps there he will
learn humility and wisdom.
- Prince Vanda, I thank you
for inviting me
to feast with you.
And you too, Durbar, for
persuading me to come.
- I always believed you to
be on the side of justice,
My Prince, let Ilya you go free.
- He boasted that he
would rule our country.
- The deed is done now.
Lead him away.
(crowd clamoring)
- [Tom] This is so bogus!
- Take him to the dungeon!
- [Mike] You know,
it would be easy
to grab the wrong
whiskery fat guy.
- If I so willed I could have
crumbled your palace into bits
but I had no wish to
spoil its decorations!
The hour will come, Prince
Vanda, when you will bow to me!
- I can be such a bitch.
- Now, lead me away,
lackeys and schemers,
I am weary of this talk.
- [Tom] Everybody's
talkin' at me.
♪ Do do do do do do do do ♪
- It is not Ilya
Muromets you have wronged
but our country herself,
you have taken the
sword from her hand!
- He speaks the truth!
We swear never to set
foot in the palace!
- [Mike] Don't we?
- You've banished us as well.
- Finland's annual
emotional outburst.
- [Tom] Uh, all for
one and one for all?
- [Mike] I'll be
in my ready room!
- Oh, I hate this thing, it
does not make me feel pretty!
- What you have done it
most unwise, my dear.
Let him go free, send
him away to a village.
He has performed many services
for our country, my dear.
- [Tom] My perky wife!
- Feed him well, mind
you, look after him.
- [Mike] Spread some
papers, give him a chew toy.
- He will repent.
That country bumpkin thinks
himself higher than the Prince,
he is much too proud,
he will never repent!
- Feed him well, I tell you.
Feed him well, I commanded it!
- [Tom] So they fed
him ice and water.
- Oh, the ice seems safe,
let's drive our pickup onto it.
- [Mike] Yes, Finland is a
four season vacation paradise.
- [Tom] I always get put
right next to the ice machine.
- [Mike] July in Minnesota!
(all chuckling)
- Okay, we get it, the
cycle of friggin' life!
- [Tom] I think
it's a film on sex.
- Feed him well, he tells me.
- [Mike] This legend could've
used some punching up.
- [Tom] The Legend of
Boggy Creek had more depth!
- That I have not
done nor will I!
- [Mike] Just empty
the chamberpot!
- He must've died of hunger.
Seven moons have passed.
I must send a signal to Sartack.
Now, swift river, you must help.
Carry my message to the Tugars
who wait this promised signal,
which will be the
sign to attack!
(splashing)
- I love you, fish!
- Hey!
What're you doing up there, eh?
- Uh, oh, heaven help me,
there was someone down!
- Whoa, whoa, I'm
Robin Williams, oh, oh!
(tearing)
- Oh, I could go
my whole life
without seein' that.
♪ And they call him the Streak ♪
- I smell fresh pants!
- [Tom] I'll make myself a
soup out of these trousers!
- Ah, this is strange.
I set a trap for a fox, I catch
a pair of breeches instead!
- [Mike] Now I am folding them
and now I'm holding this up!
- This key looks familiar,
I have seen it before.
- [Mike] Bending over now.
- Ah, this looks like trickery!
That devil is a sly one!
But I can play trick too.
- [Mike] Hey, you don't
need to convince us!
- Wacky prop comic,
Lutefisk Top!
- Wherever you like!
Where the tide takes you!
Beyond the Seventh Sea!
- [Tom] Yeah this scene sure
brings a film into sharp focus.
(dramatic music)
- Joyous news, O Exalted One!
- [Mike] I'm a bird, go away.
- Some passing merchants
have told me of the Prince.
- [Tom] Got my headphones on!
- He has thrown
Muromet into a prison
but all the nobles are
deserting for a home
and refusing to
fight! (laughing)
(Tom, Mike, and Crow laughing)
- Bring good news.
I'll destroy the infidel
who dare defy me!
- It's Boris Badenov!
- Saddle the horses!
(ominous music)
- [Mike] Oh, Siegfried & Roy!
- [Tom] Get that horse
out of my living room!
- The signal, we have just
found it in the river!
He kept his word, that sly one!
This was the single
pre-arranged.
Once again, Kalin,
I served you well!
- Let me see what you have.
- [Tom] Drop 'em!
- [Crow] He sent a pantagram!
- [Tom] I ordered Heather!
- By Beelzebub, a
pair of breeches!
- These pants have stirred
something deep inside me!
- What does it signify to you?
- [Mike] It signifies
the man had a large can.
- They are ready to
surrender to Kalin.
- [Tom] Blossom was
really funny last night
- You see, these
breeches are a symbol
of the unconquerable
might of Kalin!
- And we'll take them in!
- As it were, each
ready to herald
the power and glory
that is Kalin.
- [Mike] I don't know what
I'm talking about here.
- I see two roads here
and both of them will
lead Kalin to victory.
- Yes, victory shall
be ours finally.
- [Tom] Ah, the Golden
Age of makin' stuff up!
- The attack must be timed
according to the stars.
- You are correct.
- Sir!
- It is not yet time to attack
until the gods of
battle tell us.
We will bide our time.
- [Tom] We will wear our pants!
- Unsaddle all the horses!
- [Mike] Okay!
- [Narrator] and while Kalin
waited for a favorable sign,
Ilya Muromets rotted
in a dark dungeon,
unaware that his wife had borne
the son he so fervently wanted.
And so the months slipped by.
- [Tom] Like a pair of pants.
- You are still only a baby
and already stronger
than an oak.
- And dumber than a hammer!
- Grow, my son,
grow tall and strong
and be like your father!
- [Mike] I'm tryin'! (grunting)
- With courage like his.
- [Tom] I don't wannao
watch Power Rangers!
- And his strength as well.
- [Mike] Can I get
some breakfast or what?
- Little Falcon, my son, this
is your present from him.
- Is my face as
weird as it feels?
(creaking)
- [Tom] Burgers are ready!
- [Mike] Well...
Kiss your aunt Bernice!
- Run along and
play, little one.
- [Tom] Oh, thanks, what's the
draw strength on this thing?
Could I take down an elk?
- Why do you not love me?
- [Mike] You look like RuPaul!
- Why do you run away?
How many times must I tell you
I wish to keep you for my own?
- Never, I despise you!
- He has an outtie in
the middle of his head!
- [Tom] Who loves ya, baby?
- You shall never touch me,
Kalin, I swear it on my life!
What manner of man
are you to force me?
- Kings grovel at my feet
and so will you, my dear.
- I would sooner you threw me
into a cage of wild animals!
- [Mike] Mm, done and done.
- You will never have me!
(Kalin laughing)
- I do need a father, Mom.
(Velia gasping)
(thudding)
- I will kill you!
- [Tom] For God and country!
- Ah, the little wolf cub.
He fights, eh? (laughing)
- [Mike] I got it handled, Mom.
(Kalin grunting)
(Velia shrieking)
- [Tom] What, I'm a Mongol!
- I shall teach you how to fight
and your enemy shall
be the cursed Prince!
- Sound all right.
(tense music)
- [Mike] Uncle B.O., can
I shoot you in the back?
(thudding)
- Oh, jeez!
- [Mike] Frampton Comes Alive!
(thudding)
- Ow, jeez!
- [Mike] I've never had a
damn thing, it's astounding!
- You are still a
boy, Little Falcon,
and already you have the
strength of a warrior!
You shall challenge our
champion to a jousting bout.
- [Tom] We'll put
it on pay-per-view!
- [Kalin] Show us, Little
Falcon, whom I call my son,
how skillfully
you wield a lance.
- Michael Keaton!
- [Kalin] I know I
shall be proud of you.
(trumpets sounding)
- [Tom] The Tower of
Gourd's horn section!
- [Mike] What do I do with this?
(dramatic music)
(crowd shouting)
(yelling)
- (laughing) That's funny!
- [Mike] Where's he goin'?
Jerry!
- That's it?
I want my money back!
- [Tom] Shouldn't there be
a dragon around pretty soon?
(Kalin laughing)
- [Mike] What're
you laughin', what?
I don't get it, what?
- To the dungeon
with this weakling!
Let him guard the captives!
(laughing)
- [Crow] Sorry, something I ate.
(horse whinnying)
- Well done, Little Falcon!
You have earned the cap of
champion to wear as your own.
- [Tom] Now Mongolian
stir-fry for everyone!
- The time has come
to take up our arms!
We move at last.
(dramatic music)
- Wow, now that is a horde!
- [Mike] This is a
free festival now, man!
- I wish we had the yogurt
franchise for this horde.
- [Tom] It's kind of
a Mingus jazzy feel.
(Tom warbling)
- [Mike] Hello
little Mongol horde!
- [Tom] A giant pair
of pants back there!
- So they walked from
China to Finland?
- [Mike] Are we
goin' the right way?
- I'm just followin'
you, I don't know!
- [Tom] One guy following
along with a pooper-scooper.
- [Mike] Sounds like a concerto
for timpani and car horn.
- I'm going to
Helsinki to personally
spear that stump-throwing
son of a bitch!
- [Tom] Will the
Lawrence of Arabia people
please get to their proper sets?
(Mike humming)
- [Mike] No, keep it open,
oh great, our plan is ruined!
- [Raider] Give us 700 carts
filled with gold, Prince Vanda,
or prepares to surrender
yourself as hostage!
Almighty Chief Kalin gives
you three hours to reply.
If you refuse, your bones
will bleach you the sun!
- [Tom] It's a White
Sox pennant, I think.
- [Raider] We will take
your princess captive
for the pleasure of our chief!
- Give this reply to Kalin--
(Crow imitating fart)
What you have demanded we will
pay you in three days from now.
- [Mike] We have to call
and clear it with the bank.
- [Raider] You must
bring your tribute
to Kalin's camp at the river!
- Well, which of your nobles
will you send to fight them?
Here they are, choose one!
- Uh, heh, I gotta back
- I got a chiropractor
- To that thing I was going.
- Gee, look at the time, wow!
- He spoke truly, Ilya Muromets,
when he said there would
be many to feast with you
but none to stand
up for our land.
He spoke wisely!
- [Tom] Hey, you Mongols
need another wife?
- Oh, if only Ilya were with us,
this Kalin would not
keep us in terror!
- A collie is keeping
them in terror?
- I shall go to him and
ask his forgiveness.
- Prince, Radiant
Prince, he may be dead!
He has refused food
and drink (yelping).
- Why have you
kept this from me?
Open the dungeon!
You'll pay for this!
- [Mike] You hold a Finn by
the beard it mobilizes him.
- Wait here, Radiant Prince,
I must run and fetch the key,
I do not have it with me.
- Is this not the key?
I believe this is the
key to the dungeon, sire!
- [Tom] We have a damn
confusing kingdom here!
(upbeat music)
(tense music)
- So, you wily scoundrel,
you starved him to
death, son of misery!
- [Tom] (snoring) Hey, I just
got to sleep after 20 years!
- [Princess] He is alive, alive!
- Well, as alive as
a Finn gets, anyway.
- He lives, he is alive!
- I fed him, Prince,
as you commanded!
- He lies, my Prince.
He is the traitor who
has plotted against you.
- [Mike] He's got bedhead.
- It was this that
I came to tell you
but I was thrown into
this dark dungeon instead.
- And I wake up with
my beard in my mouth!
- That's not so,
he would have died
in this dungeon without
my bread and water!
- It was my Velia
who saved my life.
Come, I will show
you what she did.
(gentle music)
♪ I'll never smile again ♪
- [Mike] I must warn you, I've
got a weird scene goin' here.
- [Princess] A miracle,
truly a miracle!
- That's what we need!
- Forgive me, Ilya,
I have wronged you.
Help us Ilya against Kalin.
- You wish my help, Prince?
- Ilya, we need you!
- [Tom] Honey, can
I do just one thing?
- Grave danger threatens,
the Tugars stand at our gate.
- [Mike] Just two guys?
- Vast numbers of them!
- [Man] Help us, Ilya!
- Help us!
- Forget your grievance, Ilya.
- Pete Rose!
- For the people's sake.
- [Mike] Well, I thought it over
and I will definitely
not help you! (laughing)
- Not for your sake,
My Prince Vanda,
nor for the sake
of your princess.
- But for the sake of the
New Christy Minstrels.
- But for the beloved land which
gave me birth and which I love.
For her will I give my strength.
- [Tom] For the regular Joe
tryin' to make a livin'!
For the farmers!
- For you, Ilya Muromets,
my golden suit of armor!
- [Mike] We'll let it out.
- And for that traitor,
the boiling tar!
- With croutons
and melted cheese!
(Mika whimpering)
- [Mike] You know, I'd kinda
like to watch the whole
melting tar thing if
you wouldn't, what?
- Tell me, what do you
think we should do first?
- There is one thing we must
do without a moment's delay.
- Let's have lunch!
- You must summon all
of your fighting men
to your side to plan
the battle at once!
- [Mike] Do you love this man?
I love this man!
- Within three days
I will assemble
every warrior in the land!
- [Tom] You just
don't get it, do you?
(somber music)
- Well, that didn't work!
- [Tom] I claim this Mongol
for all crows everywhere!
- Crows, my brethren!
See what a grand and
noble creature they are?
- Uh-huh.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Narrator] But Kalin's
men were restless
for plunder and would not wait.
And beyond the palace,
on another plain
outside the city, they attacked!
Greatly outnumbered, the bold
defenders fought back bravely.
- [Mike] Sort of.
- [Narrator] And won the day.
But what of tomorrow?
- [Tom] Oh, I'm
gonna sleep in and,
oh,he means the movie, I forgot!
(grim dramatic music)
- Pyle!
- [Mike] Please dispose
of your Mongols properly.
- [Tom] Another
Superfund site is born!
(horse whinnying)
- Woodstock Two ends in tragedy.
- [Mike] The mass effects of
watching Pauly
Shore's last movie.
- This indeed was
a costly battle
but we had to keep
the foe in check.
- [Tom] Well, I liked it!
- Though the Prince
has wronged us sorely,
still we have fought against
the enemy who threatens us.
- Yow!
- And now we must
help him further, Alexi.
- Not even if the path be
strewn with golden coins!
I will not fight for him again!
- We must forget our feelings,
the Prince stands in his
greatest danger and he needs us!
- Would you lead me to the
Prince as once you led Ilya
for the the nobles to jeer at?
- Do you think I do not
feel about Ilya as you do,
grieving over the fate
that has befallen him?
- [Mike] Shall we dance?
- Why do you quarrel so?
- [Tom] Somethin' to do.
- Has the world grown too
narrow for both of you?
You must hasten to Ilya
Muromets, he is alive!
I have heard that he lives!
- He lives?
- Yes, he is safe and well!
- This is indeed wonderous!
- Hey!
(tense music)
- [Tom] (coughing) Excuse
me, your smoke! (coughing)
Wow!
- [Mike] Do we all
need our own campfires?
- [Tom] Must've got ahold of
some wet wood or somethin'.
(horse whinnying)
- [Mike] Bacon grease.
- [Tom] Yeah, you got yourself
quite a view from
the patio, Ilya.
- We are gonna get our
butts kicked so bad!
- [Tom] Ah, get used to
mongolian beef everybody.
- [Mike] Uh, is there a
back way outta this place?
- Hey, they took the
Golden Gate Bridge!
- The three days
have already passed,
soon the Tugars
will strike again.
- [Tom] There's a lot more
than two guys out there!
- No sign of our men.
- By myself shall go to Kalin
and persuade him to
grant us three days more.
- [Mike] Oh,
sweetheart, will you?
- Spare neither gold nor silver.
Fill new sacks to the brim
and load them on gilded carts!
- Hearken to these words from
a simple farmer, My Prince.
We will use torn sacks and
load them on old carts.
We will take but a small
portion of your treasures.
I have thought out a plan.
- [Mike] (babbling)
Mongolians. (babbling)
- You ride slowly
and drop a jewel
on the ground every 10 paces!
- [Tom] Ah, drop this, old man!
- And you drop a silver
coin at every hundred paces!
- [Mike] I'll do it later!
- And you would every
thousand paces a golden coin!
(horses whinnying)
- This is great, I can't believe
how well my plan is working!
- Prince Vanda has great
riches, I want them!
I will expect each
of you, my warriors,
to bring home much
gold from his palace.
It shall all be ours!
- [Mike] I bet you
get most of it.
- All of it outs!
(horse whinnying)
- [Tom] Will you be more
than two hours, sir?
♪ Dum dee dee dee doo dum ♪
- Mighty Chief Kalin, Prince
Vanda has sent us here
with gifts and bounty
as you have commanded!
- [Mike] Look up there, it's
the Trix are for Kids monument!
(Kalin laughing)
- So the Prince has submitted.
He is wise, your Prince.
- Yes, Kalin, here
is all the treasure.
In the first cart, silver!
- [Tom] And Nutrageous bars!
- And this one is filled
with coins of gold,
and the one beside it
is loaded with jewels!
- And we'll throw
the guy in, too!
- They're all for you!
- [Kalin] Unload the cart and
pour the gold into my sack!
- [Mike] What, you
don't like our sacks?
- [Tom] Uh, paper
or plastic, sir?
- Hey, a wheat penny!
(Kalin grunting)
- [Tom] Sega!
- [Mike] Are they having you
their cootie festival, is it?
- This is indeed unfortunate!
You see--
- It's good burlap,
I don't know what happened!
- It is quite simple.
As we prepare to leave
the palace walls,
the Prince was in great
sorrow, as you can understand.
His riches he loaded
on broken carts
and his gold he poured
into these torn sacks,
it must all have
spilled on the way here.
- [Tom] You buyin' any of this?
- And only these few
pieces of gold are left.
- Well, what're you gonna do?
- Will your men go back for
it or shall I send mine?
- [Tom] Service is
our middle name!
- I fear if I send mine,
you may not get it all.
(clanking and creaking)
(beeping)
(whirring)
(thudding)
(whooshing)
- I'm downtown!
Oh baby!
- Gimme some!
- Oh yeah!
- I got myself
made, that's great!
- Hey, someone's comin'
in on the Hexfield.
(whirring)
- Hey, it's Whoya
What's-his-face!
- Yes, it is I, Ilya Muromets!
And behold, I have a new job,
here at the legendary Pancake
House, where I am a waiter!
(laughing) Pannacookin'!
- That's great!
(all chuckling)
- And yet the day
is filled with woe,
for we are short of
staff and my great heart
is filled with sadness for
I must take Cindy's shift.
- Aw, that's, that's too bad.
- And yet, little ones,
my heart rejoices,
for behold, these short
stack of wheat cakes laden
with berries and smothered with
the cream which is whipped.
- Yum.
- And to accompany,
rashers of bacon
and beautiful links
of sausage of pork
for all to rejoice in!
- Or you can probably
get ham, huh?
- Ham.
- Mm, ham!
- Ham?
- Yeah, a little Virginia
honey-baked ham, yes!
- That is a substitution,
you spawn of the devil!
- Well now, hey hold on there!
- No one, not even a Tugar
- Hey, yo, Ilya!
- Shall order off the menu!
- Yo, Muromets!
- What?
- Hey, come on, you're Ilya
Muromets, defender of the realm!
I mean, accept this challenge,
prove to us that
you could bring ham!
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Yes, yes, I will
gather my strength
and I shall go forth and
I shall go to the back
and I shall request ham, for
it is ham that I seek, ham!
- Ham.
- Ham!
- Good luck!
- Ham, then.
(Crow laughing)
- Ham.
Good luck with the ham.
- What a stupid square head.
- Oh, not that bad.
We'll be right back.
Maybe you're right.
(upbeat music)
- Well?
- We searched all day, O
Chief, and have found no gold.
- Put him to his
death like a dog!
- [Tom] What kind
of dog, my Lord?
- Do not act in anger, Kalinm
there is no need to be
hasty about killing me.
First, you must take the
treasures that are yours!
(raider yelping)
- Hit me!
(jingling)
- He's got all our spoons!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] So when does
Ilya's plan kick in?
- He's got a Dick
Butkus intensity!
- [Mike] You're mad, aren't you?
You're mad!
(man screaming)
- That's telling
him, sir! (yelping)
- [Tom] He's worse
than Bobby Knight!
- [Mike] No, it's Bob!
- Who so ever steals
from me will die
by my own sword, like
the dog that he is!
- Come forward, chief warriors!
- [Mike] He loves
that dog thing.
- Gather every coin
and treasure, pile
it all at my feet!
- Move it, move it, move it!
- It is better to give up
the gold than lose our heads.
- Empty your pockets, huh,
the prince shall repay
us a thousand gold!
- Yes, yes, pile all
the treasure at my feet,
every piece, every coin!
- [Mike] Oh, that was
gratuitous, Ted, come on!
- [Tom] Oh, and it
goes without saying,
do it like the dogs you are!
(Tom humming)
(Kalin laughing)
- Ah, this is better
than shopping by mail!
- [Mike] Ilya's
plan seems ungainly.
- [Tom] Ah yes, Michael Ovitz
at his monthly
manager's meeting!
(clanking)
- Here, hope you choke on it!
- [Mike] There goes my
laundry money, you dickweed!
Fine!
- [Tom] Thanks to you, it's
working, the United Way!
- [Ilya] You see Chief Kalin
what great riches you have now?
- But it is not enough!
- I want Moose and Squirrel!
- I still lack one thing
to make me content.
Bring to me Ilya Muromets,
that is what I'd like!
Then shall I retreat
from your gaze.
- So shall it be, mighty Kalin!
- [Mike] Yo, baby,
you heard him!
- Return to the palace,
go to the dungeon
and seek out Ilya Muromets and
bring him back here with you,
to this very place, hurry!
- [Tom] What is his plan?
- And tell the
Prince not to dally,
there is not a moment to lose,
tell him that, do
you understand?
- Am I alone here, hello?
- O Mighty Chief Kalin, we
have searched along every road,
they're not bringing
Ilya Muromets!
- [Mike] Oh, and I made
pudding in a skull!
- You have deceived me,
emissary, and you shall die!
- I'm willing to stake
my own life on it,
Ilya Muromets will
appear before you!
- If I had Ilya
Muromets before me,
I would retreat and
withdraw my men!
- Here I stand!
(crowd gasping)
- He's a disco ball!
- Ilya Muromets!
Now withdraw your
men, you are bound
by the promise you
have made to retreat!
- [Mike] Chad, I have a
big problem with this.
- You think perhaps I am a fool.
I should chop off your head!
- I had my fingers
crossed all the time!
- But for the courage you have
shown, I might pardon you.
I shall command and you
follow, my clever emissary.
You shall be one of us.
- Never shall I serve a tyrant
or betray my native land!
We shall fight you to the end
until we have
regained our freedom!
- No we won't!
- Take your men and
retreat at once, tyrant!
We shall destroy you,
each and every one of you!
- Ah, tie him up!
- [Mike] Uh, how's this, sir?
- I wish him to be burned alive.
- Like a dog, sir?
- Drag him here to me!
I shall pull his arms
out of his sockets!
Drag him here!
- With these hands,
bloody tyrant,
I shall crush the breath
from your monstrous body!
- [Tom] Harry Houdini lives!
(Ilya whistling)
- Lassie!
- [Mike] He fooled them
into thinking tea was ready.
- [Tom] Ooh, a real sepia
tone has come over the crowd!
- After him!
I want him alive!
(dramatic music)
- Might Chief, your allies
have fled, they refuse
to join you and your men in
the attack on Prince Vanda!
- Ah!
- That felt good!
- You, you must go alone against
them and in single combat!
- [Mike] Ilya's plan is
still on, don't give up hope!
(horse whinnying)
- [Tom] This is
Arthurian in a sense
that Arthur with Dudley
Moore is Arthurian.
- Ho Ho Ha!
- I mean hi-diddly-dee!
- Send out your strongest man
to meet me in single combat!
- [Mike] Sunday, Sunday, Sunday!
- [Tom] Great, my fruitcake
son is calling me.
- Come, my young braggart
who shouts so loudly,
I am ready to beat
you in single combat!
- You are too old and feeble,
you are no match for me!
Go home, old man!
- Hey, I walk the mall!
- You must first kill
a falcon, young man,
before you bind him!
- You are afraid to fight, eh?
Now I shall show you
no mercy, old one!
(dramatic action music)
- [Mike] This movie has the
same plot as a Boy Named Sue.
(swords clashing)
- Father!
- Yes, son?
- I want to kill you, Mother?
- Guys.
- I want--
- [Mike] Guys.
- [Tom] This is gonna turn into
the Guns of Will
Sonnett now, isn't it?
(Crow groaning)
- Up, you young braggart, up!
Your strength is great!
- [Mike] Your odor
is powerful, eh!
- [Tom] I wanna
go to art school!
- Nice ring!
You get that wholesale?
(both struggling)
- [Mike] Absorbing
this into my plan,
my plan is very flexible!
- Hold, my brave young warrior,
I had not thought we would ever
meet on the field of battle.
- Why did you not kill me
when you could, old man?
I would've shown you no
mercy were I in your place!
- Be not so fiery, my
wild unbroken colt!
Tell me your name, young man,
and what do they call you?
Who are your father and mother?
- I have no mother, I
have never seen her!
I am Little Falcon,
the son of Kalin!
- What you say is not
true, I am your father!
- Oh great, my dad's Burl Ives!
- Do you speak the
truth, old man?
Is this really the truth?
- Yes, I speak the truth!
Look now, I will show you.
- [Ton] I got a little
birthmark on my left buttcheek.
- See, this is my
ring you are wearing.
- [Mike] You
graduated at '83 too?
(somber music)
- [Tom] Wow, they get the
Family Channel on the ring!
- [Mike] It's the
little Dutch boy!
- It is as though in a vision.
I see my mother!
- Mom!
- Oh Father, will you ever
forgive me for what I have done?
- [Tom] Why did
you lick me, son?
- And now I wish to
fight with all my power
for the Prince and you!
- [Mike] Kid's loyalty
turns on a dime!
- No, my son, I have a plan.
- [Tom] Oh no!
- First, you must go back
and find your mother, boy.
You will know her by the
scar on her right cheek
from the sword of one
of Kalin's Tugars.
- Kind of a long way, Dad,
is there a bus or somethin'?
- We must pretend to fight,
they are watching us!
Strike me, Father,
with all your strength!
- [Tom] I want
every penny's worth!
- [Mike] Geez who
am I, Gary Crosby?
- Kill them all!
Massacre every one of them!
All the young, women,
children, spare no one!
- Ilya's plan moves
into phase nine.
- You will take the
left flank, Alexi.
- [Mike] I like white meat!
- And Durbar's men will
follow along the right flank
and I will lead my men through
the center of their ranks.
The Prince remains here with
his men to defend a palace.
- [Mike] Foghat
prepares for war!
(crowd shouting)
- [Tom And Crow] No
rain, no rain, no rain!
- [Tom] We are live from
beautiful Trojan Stadium today!
- That is one Irish-Catholic
family! (whistling)
- [Mike] The cattle
call for Sound of Music!
♪ The hills are alive ♪
♪ The hills are alive
with the sound of ♪
- Run away!
50,000 Maria von Trapps face
off against the Mongol horde!
(upbeat music)
- Who among you knows my mother?
- [Mike] She died.
(somber music)
- Come on people,
let's wake up in here!
- I know she is somewhere
in this dungeon.
- [Tom] You're not supposed
to be on this floor!
- She has a small scar
on her right cheek,
it is the remembrance
of a Tugar's sword.
- [Mike] Now I was a
baby when I last saw her,
so I'll need to see
all your breasts.
- Are you Irene Papas?
- Mother, forgive me!
Mother?
Do not send me away,
please forgive me!
- [Tom] Go watch TV!
- Please.
I have found my true father!
- [Mike] Did you follow
the trail of beer cans?
- He sends you his love.
- Did he send any money?
- My boy!
- [Tom] You have a weird face.
- I could really use
my boy right now.
(crowd shouting)
- [Mike] Better check
that boat for milfoil.
- [Tom] What a rotten
Trojan horse there!
- Hoist the sails!
After them!
Down with the Tugars!
(dramatic music)
(swords clashing)
- We fight for Dolly Madison!
- [Mike] Oh, everyone thought
to bring a light wrap.
- [Tom] Vroom,
vroom, here we go!
Vroom, vroom!
- Could someone invent water?
- [Mike] And still more Marias!
♪ The hills are alive ♪
- Form a mountain of men, hey!
- [Tom] Hog pile on Jim!
- I wish to see the
strength of the enemy!
I must know the size of the
force he pits against me!
- No need to explain, sir, we
like making mountains of men!
- Higher!
Highe, higher!
♪ I wanna take you higher ♪
- [Mike] The trick here is to be
one of the last
ones on the pile.
- [Crow] It's a Tugar pileup!
- [Tom] Hey, you got your
elbow in my groin, ugh.
- Oh, I need to move my face.
- Would you get your--
- Oh, my--
- [Tom] What is
that, ugh, it's soft!
- Come rally to
my side, warriors,
and I will show you where Prince
Vanda and his cowards hide!
- I shall be the
echo, (spitting)
responding to his call.
- [Mike] The first product
to the Acme company.
(thudding)
- Ha ha!
(men screaming)
(men groaning)
(spitting)
- My fillings!
- Go now, to the gate,
release Zuma the Fire Dragon!
The palace will be nothing
but ashes and smoke!
- [Mike] Can we get up now?
(Zuma roaring)
- It's Ghidorah!
- [Mike] Okay, we're goin' left.
- [Tom] I say we're goin' right!
- Will you two quit arguing?
I'll decide!
- Oh, shut up!
- No, we're goin' left!
- I swear--
- We're goin' left!
- They sent their fire
dragon, they have released it!
- Go, Little Falcon, you must
go back and help them now.
- No, I will not
leave you here alone!
- No harm shall come to me,
I will find my way
home safely, my son.
- [Tom] Admit it, we're lost!
- [Mike] This baby
can handle everything
but a three-headed
dra, oh son of a, oh!
(whooshing)
(people screaming)
- [Tom] I love the smell of
dragon breath in the morning!
- This dragon of
theirs breathes fire
but we will extinguish him.
Look, he flies
like a nightingale!
- I heard that, I do
not fly like that!
(clanking)
(thudding)
(Zuma roaring)
- Look, the spear, it hit him!
- [Mike] Help the bombardier!
(men shouting)
(Zuma roaring)
- I'll handle this, guys.
- [Tom] Well, if you're sure!
- Yeah, you two run along.
- Okay!
(fire roaring)
- [Mike] Oh, the poor
little guy's just scared!
(Zuma roaring)
- [Tom] Well, the point
of having the dragon
is to tell the world
you have a dragon,
why did you keep it a secret?
(dramatic music)
- Aw shoot, I just
waxed that boat!
(swords clashing)
- [Tom] I love my job!
- The Prince shall be killed,
when we are the
victors Muromets dies!
He shall be burned alive!
(Zuma roaring)
- Dragonslayer II:
The Uncalled For!
(Tom and Crow imitating sirens)
- [Mike] August
Strindberg's Backdraft!
(intense action music)
- [Tom] Now for the best
part of my plan, retreat!
- Ooh, get that dragon
the world's biggest mint!
(Mike laughing goofily)
(whooshing)
- [Tom] Thank you!
(people shouting)
- Hello, I'm on fire, oh!
- Fiery dragon!
Oh, his breath, it
is like our oven!
- [Mike] Hi, can I help you?
You seem like, ugh!
(swords clashing
- Is somebody putting
away the silverware?
- Father, together we shall
send this fiery monster
back to the hell he came from!
- [Mike] Little
Thelonious Falcon,
you get down from
there right now!
- [Tom] How come I
always have to carve?
- Water!
(splashing)
- Not for me!
(thudding)
- [Tom] Hey, dragon
head, all right!
- [Mike] Great, dragon
sandwiches for the next month.
- Follow me, warriors,
the enemy is in retreat!
We shall drive
them into the sea!
- Horse looks like Stallone!
- [Tom] Ilya's Plan is still
being taught at West Point!
- Gee, the sky is as
clear as Gary, Indiana!
- [Mike] You know, now I have
an unhealthy hatred
of Finnish people.
- I suppose, huh?
- Well, yeah, you know
we've been on the
Earth quite a while.
- It's Miller Time.
- Better get back home.
- [Tom] If don't wanna
ride those horses,
you could take the
fjord! (laughing)
- [Mike] Should we
make a big mountain?
- No, we won't have to
make a big mountain!
- [Mike] I just was asking!
- [Tom] Foxy lady!
- Back, back cowards, fight!
- [Mike] Oh! (sobbing)
- God of Battle,
listen to my oath!
Spare me and I shall
serve you, I promise this!
- Ooh, is there a dipping sauce?
- Prepare to die,
dog of a Kalin!
- Spare me, I beg
of you, be merciful!
Spare a handful of Tugars,
please, so we may beget sons!
- Stay your hand, warrior!
Our people shall judge
the fate of Kalin!
- Let us take him
alive to the palace.
Treat him like the
cur that he is,
stuff him in a sack and
carry him back to the palace!
- Huh?
- Oh, those guys
are so fun at times like this!
(laughing)
- [Tom] Oh, if you can
laugh once in a war...
- So ends the
mighty Chief Kalin.
♪ The hills are in flames ♪
(triumphant music)
- Ilya, my love!
- I have some things to explain
about me and the wind demon.
- Velia, my dearest.
- [Mike] I wanna feel ya, Ilya.
- At last I found you!
- [Tom] Hey, they
captured Billy Barty!
- [Mike] Oh, it's
Housing Project Hill.
- I have Rockports!
- In your honor, Ilya,
we shall have a feast!
- [Mike] Now get back
to the dungeon, you!
- Henceforth Ilya, you
shall live in the palace,
you shall become a
noble or a prince.
- [Tom] Or somethin'.
- I thank you, My Prince,
but I could not
live at the palace.
- It stinks in there!
- I must pursue my destiny,
I must go where
adventure leads me!
- [Mike] I'm joining
the Hogan Tour!
- The road to life has
many different paths.
This brave and willing soldier,
he will serve you well
at court, he is my son.
- So be it.
We shall be proud to have with
us the son of Ilya Muromets.
- Even though he is
a Mongol bastard!
- Bring no dishonor for the
magic sword of Invincor.
- [Mike] Gee, Dad, it's a Daisy!
- [Tom] Ow, I cut myself!
- I accept this sword and I
shall honor it always, Father.
- Bravo, Ilya Murmomets, bravo!
- Bravo respects the
rights of the artists.
- [Mike] But Ilya's
son did bring dishonor,
he traded the sword for a lid
and got high in the palace.
(Crow laughing)
♪ So long country bumpkin ♪
♪ Fresh as frost
out on the pumpkin ♪
♪ I've seen some sights ♪
(clanking and creaking)
(beeping)
(whirring)
(thudding)
(whooshing)
- Did you hear Kate
Mulgrew is Mrs. Picard?
- Yes!
- Hey guys, I got ahold
of the first edition
of Gypsy review of our
political satirical review!
- Oh yeah!
- Oh, don't read that stuff,
why feel bad if
you don't have to?
- Oh, come on Mike, I'm
sure you got a mention!
Now let's take a look here.
Alrighty, here goes!
Ahem,
"As I
watched
Supercalafragalisticexpiala-wacky
"one question
clawed at my brain.
"Does such delight actually
dwell in the universe?"
Here it comes!
"The answer is
yes yes yes," hey!
"And it comes in a big blond
package called Mike Nelson!"
- Hey!
- Well, there you go!
- "Bright and irreverent,
Mr. Nelson thrills the viewer
"with his charismatic
presence," (laughing)
"what a treat this man is!"
- Whoa!
- "Mr. Servo, however,
bounded on the..."
- Yeah?
- Um, ahem, "Mr. Servo
however bounded on the stage
"shrieking his lines
shrill as a fishwife.
"Who or what put
this man on stage?"
Brr!
"Crow T. Robot
rounds out the cast."
- Well, hey, you really
did round out the cast!
- I did?
- Yeah, you did.
- All right!
- And you, I mean, a
fishwife, that's good.
- That's a good thing.
- That's good, right?
'Cause what is a fishwife
but chopped fish?
Hey look, the things, the guys.
- Oh, yeah!
- The guys are calling.
- Hey, Nelstoney! (chuckling)
Probably noticed all the skirts
runnin' around down here.
Place was lousy with 'em.
Well, they're gone now but if
they were still here, boom!
(both chuckling)
- Yep, there're four words to
describe the climate down here
va va va voom! (chuckling)
You know, Clay,
you and I should go
cruisin' for some
more lady loves.
- Ah, no doubt,
no doubt Frankie,
but I've gotta bag up the rest
of my Animal Man collection.
If it weren't for that, pa-poom!
- Understood, my
friend, understood.
It's like me, right
now I'd go out
cruisin' for some
more lady loves
but there're three very
good reasons why I can't:
Universal Action Pack!
(phone ringing)
(both yelping)
(chill music)
(dramatic music)
(crashing)